

Profile

Passionate and motivated software developer based in Milan with 2 years of professional experience developing with C# and Unity.

Interested in all kinds of technologies, in particular everything regarding Shaders, Videogames, AR/VR/XR, and AI.

I think the best part of our job is to find a new problem to solve and nothing gratifies me more than doing it.

I've spent five years working in the family business to pay for my studies, which's lead me to understand even more how much I love coding and in particular solving problems.

Employment History

Software Developer, OverIT - Field Service Management, Milano

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

I am currently working on AR technlogies with Microsoft Holens 2 for the SPACE1 division to develop new solutions for the Field Service Menagement and the Augmented Collaboration

Software Developer (C# - Unity), UpSurgeOn Srl, Milano

MARCH 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2021

UpSurgeOn develops an advanced sequence of virtual and physical technologies designed to support mental and manual training for young neurosurgeons. The goal of the company is to solve the problem of practice in neurosurgery which is a global healthcare emergency.

For this purpose, UpSurgeOn won the European Union's H2020 Research and Innovation Programme under grant agreement n.880895.

During my period working there as a Software developer on Unity I was able to focus on:

C#, Unity, Online Stores Management, ARCore - ARKit, Shaders, UI, In-Depth Code optimization, Services (Savings, In-App Purchase, News), Database, Online Server API, Camera Behaviours.

Professor of "Shader Basics", The Sign Comics & Arts Academy, Florence

OCTOBER 2019 - MARCH 2020

The Sign Comics & Arts Academy is a private university that offers courses on all kinds of subjects related to game development.

After my graduation, the academy offered me a six months job as a professor to teach new programmers my thesis' topics. It was a very incredible experience that helped me to become more aware of my knowledge.

Education

Details

Milan

Italy

+39 3935667302

giacomo_vanni@yahoo.it

NATIONALITY

Italian

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

22/11/1993

Pontedera (Pisa)

Links

Portfolio with all of my projects

Skills

C#

Unity

Git

Shader (CG - HLSL)

C++

OOP

HTML-CSS

Working with Designers/Artists

Languages

Italian

English

Hobbies

Videogames, Card games, Tennis, Skiing, Cooking

Game Programmer, Event Horizon School / TheSign Comics & Arts Academy , Florence

SEPTEMBER 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2019

Final thesis: Shader (CG-HLSL).

Three-year course with focus on:

C#, C++, Unity, Teamwork, Working with artists and designers, working with other developers, multiplatform.

Computer Engineering, University of Pisa

SEPTEMBER 2014 - NOVEMBER 2016

Although I didn't complete the course, I spent two years attending classes and exams.

I learned the principles of Programming, OOP, and attended courses of Algorithm and Data Structures, Operating System, Math and Physic

Courses

Shader Development using Unity,

https://shaderdev.com/p/shader-development-using-unity-5

JANUARY 2018 - JANUARY 2019

Extra-curricular activities

Receptionist, Dimora Antico Borgo, Terricciola

JANUARY 2012 - JANUARY 2019

To pay for my studies I've joined the family business handling social media and welcoming customers for our B&B/apartment service in Tuscany. There I learned how to work and relate with people.

Internships

Unity Developer (Microsoft HoloLens), Balzo Srl, Florence

MAY 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2016

After I've finished my first year at the academy, one of my professors offered me an internship at his company.

For four months I've worked hand to hand with senior developers using Microsoft HoloLens.

References

References available upon request